<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Kitsune</name>
		<description></description>
		<author url="https://www.dandwiki.com/wiki/Kitsune,_9th_Variant_(5e_Race)">DnD 5E Homebrew Wiki</author>
		<update version="0.0.6">
			<file name="race-kitsune.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mFireworks/AuroraContent/main/VC-Adventures/races/race-kitsune.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

    <element name="Kitsune" type="Race" source="VC Adventures" id="ID_RACE_KITSUNE">
        <description>
            <h4>PHYSICAL DESCRIPTION</h4>
            <p>Physically, kitsune are noted for having as many as nine tails. Generally, a greater number of tails indicates an older and or more powerful fox. To most people kitsune look like normal foxes but slightly bigger or large like a dog, but more magically attuned. They can see that they have unique colored markings on their body. In human form they look like any other human but they have the ears and tail(s) of their fox form, they can choose to hide the ears and tail(s) if they wish.</p>

            <h4>HISTORY</h4>
            <p>Kitsune have long been a race that hides from the world in the deep forests. often the random one will leave the forest to live among the people in disguise, while others sneak into the towns and villages to play pranks on the people living there. Other regions of the world that know of these beings think that they are magical and that they would grant them power of ever caught to regain their freedom.</p>

            <h4>SOCIETY</h4>
            <p>Many tales are told about the Kitsune most only known as myths. Not many have seen the Kitsune or if they have they did not know it. Many people see Kitsune: some see the Kitsune as merely myths and that they have seen no proof that they exist, some fear them for the tricks they pull thinking that they seek to lure and kidnap people, and others see them as deities worth giving worship to.</p>

            <h4>KITSUNE NAMES</h4>
            <p>Names Kitsune can have.</p>
            <p class="indent">Aisiri, Akane, Akemi, Akio, Amaterasu, Ashinsen, Ayame, Bemei, Chieko, Chinatsu, Dai, Daisuke, Dawn, Domino, Eiji, Emiko, Fujin, Fumio, Gina, Genji, Hachiman, Hanako, Haruhi, Haruka, Haruki, Hisashi, Hikari, Hyosuki, Ichiro, Ikumi, Inari, Jiro, Jun, Junko, Kaede, Kaeya, Kameko, Kaida, Kaito, Katsumi, Kenji, Kiku, Kimiko, Kin, Kiyoko, Kiyoshi, Koji, Kou, Makato, Maki, Masanori, Masaru, Masayoshi, Michi, Michio, Midori, Minako, Minoru, Mokei, Naoki, Natsumi, Nariyama, Nimiaki, Nonabu, Osamu, Ren, Ryo, Ryuu, Sakura, Sayuri, Satoru, Shinichi, Tadao, Tadashi, Takumi, Takeshi, Tomio, Toshiaki, Tsuneo, Tsuyoshi, Yori, Yuki, Yuji, Yumi, Zenkichi</p>

            <h4>KITSUNE TRAITS</h4>
            <p>A race of humanoid, anthropomorphic fox people who are coveted for their power, and infamously known for their shapeshifting abilities from a fox.</p>
            <p>
                <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span>Your Charisma score increases by 1 and your Dexterity score increases by 1.<br />
                <span class="feature">Age.</span>Kitsunes mature slowly, achieving adulthood at around 100 and live up to a 1000 years<br />
                <span class="feature">Alignment.</span>Kitsune are beings of a chaotic nature, similar to their creator "Inari". Whether they are good, evil or somewhere in between is defined by how they choose to live.<br />
                <span class="feature">Size.</span>Kitsune are often found between 5 feet to 6 feet tall in human form, fixing them in a medium size. when they revert to their fox forms, they are reduced to small size.<br />
                <span class="feature">Speed.</span>Your base walking speed is 30 feet. In fox form, your speed increases to 40 feet.<br />
                <span class="feature">Darkvision.</span>As creatures of fey magic and trickery, kitsune can see in darkness as well as in light. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You cant discern color in darkness, only shades of grey<br/>
                <span class="feature">Agility.</span>Kitsune are agile beings, moving with purpose and grace. as such, they gain proficiency in Acrobatics<br/>
                <span class="feature">True Form.</span>You can transform between fox and human form at will. In combat, this takes an action. Human form can look any way you desire, gender being the same as your chosen gender. You may speak as normal and use kitsune magic while in fox form. When changing to fox form, all Armour falls to the ground, when changing to human, you appear wearing a conjured set of clothing.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Casting.</span>Kitsune can cast cantrips in both forms.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Kitsune Bite.</span>In fox form, Kitsune has a bite attack that deals 1d6 piercing damage to their target.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Kitsune Claw.</span>In fox form, Kitsune has a claw attack that deals 1d6 piercing or slashing damage to their target depending how the kitsune would use their claws. Example: The kistune would jump on the target digging there claws into the target = 1d6 piercing damage. The kistune would get to the target and would hit the target = 1d6 slashing damage<br/>
                <span class="feature">Kitsune Magic.</span>You Know the Dancing Lights and Produce Flame.
                    <ul>
                        <li>Once you reach 3rd level, you can cast Charm person once per long rest as a 2nd level spell.</li>
                        <li>Once you reach 5th level, you can also cast Invisibility as a 3rd level spell once per long rest.</li>
                        <li>Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</li>
                    </ul><br/>
                <span class="feature">Kitsune Tails.</span>You gain more tails as you gain more power starting with a second tail at level 4 you gain 1 tail every 2 levels until level 18.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Languages.</span>You can speak, read, and write Common and Sylvan and one other language of your choice. Plus you can speak to other animals/creasts/beasts.<br />
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <setters>
            <set name="names">Aisiri, Akane, Akemi, Akio, Amaterasu, Ashinsen, Ayame, Bemei, Chieko, Chinatsu, Dai, Daisuke, Dawn, Domino, Eiji, Emiko, Fujin, Fumio, Gina, Genji, Hachiman, Hanako, Haruhi, Haruka, Haruki, Hisashi, Hikari, Hyosuki, Ichiro, Ikumi, Inari, Jiro, Jun, Junko, Kaede, Kaeya, Kameko, Kaida, Kaito, Katsumi, Kenji, Kiku, Kimiko, Kin, Kiyoko, Kiyoshi, Koji, Kou, Makato, Maki, Masanori, Masaru, Masayoshi, Michi, Michio, Midori, Minako, Minoru, Mokei, Naoki, Natsumi, Nariyama, Nimiaki, Nonabu, Osamu, Ren, Ryo, Ryuu, Sakura, Sayuri, Satoru, Shinichi, Tadao, Tadashi, Takumi, Takeshi, Tomio, Toshiaki, Tsuneo, Tsuyoshi, Yori, Yuki, Yuji, Yumi, Zenkichi</set>
            <set name="names-format">{{name}}</set>
            <set name="height" modifier="1d12">5'</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="charisma" value="1" />
            <stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
            <stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
            <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_SYLVAN" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_TRUE_FORM" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_BITE" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_CLAWS" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_MAGIC" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_TAILS" />
        </rules>
    </element>
  
    <element name="True Form" type="Racial Trait" source="VC Adventures" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_TRUE_FORM">
        <description>
            <p>You can transform between fox and human form at will. In combat, this takes an action. Human form can look any way you desire, gender being the same as your chosen gender. You may speak as normal and use kitsune magic while in fox form. When changing to fox form, all Armour falls to the ground, when changing to human, you appear wearing a conjured set of clothing.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description>You can transform between fox and human form at will. In combat, this takes an action. You may speak as normal and use kitsune magic while in fox form. When changing to fox form, all Armour falls to the ground, when changing to human, you appear wearing a conjured set of clothing.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Kitsune Bite" type="Racial Trait" source="VC Adventures" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_BITE">
        <description>
            <p>In fox form, Kitsune has a bite attack that deals 1d6 piercing damage to their target.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>In fox form, Kitsune has a bite attack that deals 1d6 piercing damage to their target.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Kitsune Claws" type="Racial Trait" source="VC Adventures" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_CLAWS">
        <description>
            <p>In fox form, Kitsune has a claw attack that deals 1d6 piercing or slashing damage to their target depending how the kitsune would use their claws. Example: The kistune would jump on the target digging there claws into the target = 1d6 piercing damage. The kistune would get to the target and would hit the target = 1d6 slashing damage</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>In fox form, Kitsune has a claw attack that deals 1d6 piercing or slashing damage to their target depending how the kitsune would use their claws.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Kitsune Magic" type="Racial Trait" source="VC Adventures" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_MAGIC">
        <description>
            <p>You Know the Dancing Lights and Produce Flame.
                    <ul>
                        <li>Once you reach 3rd level, you can cast Charm person once per long rest as a 2nd level spell.</li>
                        <li>Once you reach 5th level, you can also cast Invisibility as a 3rd level spell once per long rest.</li>
                        <li>Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</li>
                    </ul></p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As you grow as a Kitsune, you'll gain access to different spells.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DANCING_LIGHTS" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRODUCE_FLAME" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_PERSON" level="3"/>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVISIBILITY" level="5"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Kitsune Tails" type="Racial Trait" source="VC Adventures" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_TAILS">
        <description>
            <p>You gain more tails as you gain more power starting with a second tail at level 4 you gain 1 tail every 2 levels until level 18.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain more tails as you gain more power starting with a second tail at level 4 you gain 1 tail every 2 levels until level 18.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>